Christopher M. Miller

Chicago, IL 60618 | cmiller0189@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/christophermllr

Professional Profile

Christopher Miller specializes in application development strategy, design, and delivery as well as enterprise architecture and integration. He brings over ten years of experience developing solutions using technologies like ASP.NET, Angular, JavaScript, and Microsoft Azure and has led delivery teams through multiple complex engagements. Primarily focused on helping Energy and Utilities clients as they navigate an evolving technology landscape, Christopher has also developed applications and advised clients on technology strategy across the healthcare, retail, food science, private equity, and higher education industries.

Experience

Director, West Monroe | Chicago, IL

Mar 2021 — Present

Senior Architect, West Monroe | Chicago, IL

Mar 2019 — Feb 2021

- Led implementations of Intellio™ Connect at multiple electric utilities to accelerate distributed energy resource (DER) deployment
- Architected the IT/OT integration strategy for a utility's Advanced Distribution Management System implementation
- Designed a digital product integration strategy and architecture for a perioperative healthcare client
- Designed a future state enterprise architecture/strategy for back-office systems at a large healthcare professional association
- Achieved West Monroe's Sequoia Award for mentorship in 2019

Architect, West Monroe | Chicago, IL

Oct 2015 — Feb 2019

- Advised a large healthcare professional association on technology modernization strategy and SDLC process improvements
- Managed delivery teams across multiple Intellio™ Connect projects including payment integration and public API management
- Led modernization efforts for a large benefits administrator's core platform technology and software development processes
- Executed an intranet platform assessment for a large utility and created a customer data IT strategy roadmap for a large retailer
- Managed and delivered development projects for a large medical equipment manufacturer's inventory management system
- Managed and delivered development projects for a global food testing organization's lab result system
- Executed an SDLC assessment for a global payment processing company to optimize their development organization
- Performed over ten technical software due diligence projects for private equity clients

Senior Consultant, *West Monroe* | Chicago, IL Experienced Consultant, *West Monroe* | Chicago, IL Consultant, *West Monroe* | Chicago, IL Oct 2013 — Oct 2015

Oct 2012 — Oct 2013

Jun 2011 — Oct 2012

Education

B.S. with Highest Distinction, Computer and Information Technology, *Purdue University* | West Lafayette, IN Certificate in Entrepreneurship & Innovation, *Purdue University* | West Lafayette, IN

Dec 2010 Dec 2010

Technical Qualifications

- Back-end development: ASP.NET, Java/Spring, and Python
- Front-end development: Angular/TypeScript, AngularJS/JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, ¡Query, Bootstrap
- Data: Microsoft SQL Server, SQL Azure, Apache Cassandra, DataStax Enterprise
- Management: Agile, engagement lead, and technical architecture experience with mid-sized teams of 3-7 developers
- Deployment/administration: Azure App Service, Azure Service Bus, other Azure components, IIS, SQL Server, Jenkins CI

Certifications and Publications

- Microsoft Certified Web Developer: Web Applications, Certified Cassandra Architect, and DataStax Certified Architect
- Sheppard, Dennis, Christopher Miller, and A. J. Liptak. AngularJS for. NET Developers in 24 Hours. Sams: Indianapolis, IN, 2015. Print.